# COREY YOUNG

cmyoung0718@gmail.com

**5**02-541-8833

**♀** Seattle, WA

in corey-young-0718

#### **Skills**

#### **DATA SKILLS**

Python (Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas)

Machine Learning

Data Analysis

Experimental Design

Natural Language Processing

Data Cleansing and Manipulation

SQL

Data Visualization (Tableau, MatPlotLib, Seaborn)

MongoDB

#### **BIOLOGY SKILLS**

Experimental Design Cell/Tissue Culture PCR

Aseptic Technique

#### **Awards**

University of Louisville

School of Aug Interdisciplinary 2014 and Graduate Studies Fellowship Fellowship that paid tuition and stipend during my time in the University of Louisville's Biology PhD program

# **Summary**

Data scientist with a passion for data, research, and science. I strive to utilize my problem solving skills and curiosity to use data to achieve better health care, find solutions for social change, and improve scientific research. I have a background in biological research that helped me to develop a love for research and data. My time at General Assembly added to my knowledge and skills in programming, data analysis, machine learning, big data, and recommendation systems.

# **Experience**

## General Assembly

Data Science Immersive

Seattle, WA 2016 to Current

- Three month intensive course, around 75 hours a week
- Completed projects utilizing machine learning algorithms in Python under strict time constraints
- Gained the experience and training I needed to take the step from biology to data science
- Strengthened my skills in Python (Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Numpy, MatPlotLib, etc), SQL, MongoDB, Git, command line, machine learning, and data engineering.

# The Commonwealth of Kentucky

Forensic Biologist 1

Frankfort, KY 2015 to 2016

- Screened evidence for the presence of body fluids using a variety of techniques, including immunodiffusion tests and the Kastle-Meyer test.
- Prepared chemical reagents used for the screening of evidence
- Received evidence from police agencies around the state according to the Case Acceptance Policy

### University of Louisville

Research Assistant

Louisville, KY 2012 to 2015

- · Designed protocols and performed experiments accordingly
- Analyzed data to gain insight into how Salmonella is able to cause systemic infections
- Responsible for training and supervising new research assistants
- Helped to develop a new in vitro assay to study how Salmonella causes systemic infections
- Helped secure a federal grant worth over \$500,000

## **Education**

General Assembly
Data Science Immersive 2016

University of Louisville Graduate Work

University of Louisville BA in Biology 2014

#### **Activities**

I am also very interested in all things music. I am a mostly self-taught guitarist with a moderate amount of knowledge in music theory.